All from the simple setup that I actually described. So my wife has been field testing some of our microscopes by washing my clothes whenever I forget them in the dryer. So it turns out they're waterproof, and -- (Laughter) — right here is just fluorescent water, and I don't know if you can actually see this. This also shows you how the projection scope works. You get to see the beam the way it's projected and bent. Can we get the lights back on again? So I'm quickly going to show you, since I'm running out of time, in terms of how much it costs for us to manufacture, the biggest idea was roll-to-roll manufacturing, so we built this out of 50 cents of parts and costs. (Applause) And what this allows us to do is to think about a new paradigm in microscopy, which we call use-and-throw microscopy. I'm going to give you a quick snapshot of some of the parts that go in. Here is a sheet of paper. This is when we were thinking about the idea. This is an A4 sheet of paper. These are the three stages that you actually see. And the optical components, if you look at the inset up on the right, we had to figure out a way to manufacture lenses in paper itself at really high throughputs, so it uses a process of self-assembly and surface tension to build achromatic lenses in the paper itself. So that's where the lenses go. There are some light sources. And essentially, in the end, all the parts line up because of origami, because of the fact that origami allows us micron-scale precision of optical alignment. So even though this looks like a simple toy, the aspects of engineering that go in something like this are fairly sophisticated. So here is another obvious thing that we would do, typically, if I was going to show that these microscopes are robust, is go to the third floor and drop it from the floor itself. There it is, and it survives. So for us, the next step actually is really finishing our field trials. We are starting at the end of the summer. We are at a stage where we'll be making thousands of microscopes. That would be the first time where we would be doing field trials with the highest density of microscopes ever at a given place. We've started collecting data for malaria, Chagas disease and giardia from patients themselves. And I want to leave you with this picture. I had not anticipated this before, but a really interesting link between hands-on science education and global health. What are the tools that we're actually providing the kids who are going to fight this monster soup for tomorrow? I would love for them to be able to just print out a Foldscope and carry them around in their pockets. Thank you. (Applause)
Todo a partir de la configuración simple que describí. Mi esposa ha hecho pruebas de campo con algunos de estos microscopios lavando mi ropa cuando los olvido en la secadora. Así que resulta que son a prueba de agua y... (Risas) aquí hay agua fluorescente, y no sé si en realidad se puede ver esto. Esto también muestra cómo funciona el alcance de la proyección. Pueden ver el rayo, cómo se proyecta y se curva. ¿Podemos encender las luces de nuevo? Rápidamente les mostraré, porque me estoy quedando sin tiempo, lo que nos cuesta fabricarlo. La idea principal era la fabricación de rollo a rollo, así construimos este a 50 centavos de partes y costos. (Aplausos) Y esto nos permite pensar en un nuevo paradigma en microscopía, que llamamos microscopía de usar y tirar. Les daré un panorama general de algunas de las partes involucradas. Esta es una hoja de papel. Aquí estábamos pensando la idea. Esta es una hoja de papel A4. Estas son las 3 etapas que ven. Y los componentes ópticos, si miran el recuadro arriba a la derecha, teníamos que encontrar una manera de fabricar lentes en papel para muy altas producciones, por eso usa un proceso de autoensamblado y tensión superficial para construir lentes acromáticas en el propio papel. Ahí van las lentes. Hay algunas fuentes de luz. Y, esencialmente, a la postre, todas las piezas se alinean gracias al origami, gracias a que el origami nos permite una precisión a escala micrométrica de la alineación óptica. A pesar de parecer un juguete sencillo, los aspectos de ingeniería que contiene algo como esto son bastante sofisticados. Aquí vemos otra cosa obvia que hicimos típicamente para demostrar que estos microscopios son robustos, fuimos al tercer piso y lo dejamos caer al suelo. Ahí está, y sobrevive. Para nosotros, el siguiente paso en realidad es terminar las pruebas de campo. Estamos empezando a finales del verano. Estamos en una etapa en la que haremos miles de microscopios. Esa sería la primera vez que estaríamos haciendo pruebas de campo con la mayor densidad de microscopios en un lugar dado. Hemos empezado la recolección de datos para la malaria, la enfermedad de Chagas y la giardia de los propios pacientes. Y quiero dejarles esta imagen. Yo no lo había previsto, pero es un vínculo muy interesante entre la educación práctica en ciencias y la salud mundial. ¿Cuáles son las herramientas que les estamos dando a los niños que van a combatir esta sopa monstruosa mañana? Me encantaría que ellos pudieran imprimir un pliegoscopio y llevárselo en sus bolsillos. Gracias. (Aplausos)